In the last lecture we made sure that our navigation items and the logo and everything looks good on
Podczas ostatniego wykadu upewnilimy si, e nasze elementy nawigacyjne i logo oraz
both desktop and mobile devices,
wszystko wyglda dobrze na komputerach i urzdzeniach mobilnych.
that's cool.
To super.
Let's make sure we all have a backdrop behind the sidebar
Upewnijmy si, e wszyscy mamy to za tymi bocznymi.
and I also of course want to ensure that we can open and close it dynamically.
I oczywicie chc rwnie, abymy mogli dynamicznie otwiera i zamyka.
Let's start with the backdrop, the backdrop should be behind to sideDrawer and we already have a backdrop
Zacznijmy od ta, w ktrym to powinno znajdowa si za szuflad, a my ju
component in the UI folder
mamy element ta w folderze UI.
but how do we best add it to the sideDrawer?
Ale jak najlepiej doda do bocznej szuflady.
Well just as I added it to the modal, I included it in the modal component, I want to include it in the
Kiedy dodaem go do ruchliwego elementu doczonego do modalnego komponentu, poczyem go take z
sideDrawer component too because it belongs to the sideDrawer.
komponentem, poniewa naley on do bocznej szuflady.
So for that, I will import the backdrop in my sideDrawer component file, so import backdrop from
W zwizku z tym zaimportuj to z mojej strony narysuj plik komponentu, a nastpnie zaimportuj to z.
and now let's go up 2 levels, then into the UI folder, into the backdrop folder and import it from the
A teraz przejdmy do 2 poziomw, a nastpnie przejdmy do folderu UI w folderze backdrop i
backdrop.js file
zaimportujmy go z pliku js.
and let's add backdrop here in the sideDrawer.
I dodajmy to w bocznej szufladzie.
Now you got this wrapping element with the which basically styles my sideDrawer and the modal should
Teraz masz ten element owijajcy z D, w ktrym w zasadzie szuflada Stahl jest moj boczn szuflad, a modelant powinien
sit outside of it otherwise it would be contained inside the sideDrawer and that's of course exactly
siedzie z boku, mdry, e bdzie zawarty w bocznej szufladzie, a to oczywicie nie
not what I want. Outside of it,
jest to, czego chc poza tym.
use the problem that we have adjacent jsx elements but we can simply import our auxiliary component
Zobaczysz problem z ssiadujcymi elementami GSX, ale moemy po prostu zaimportowa nasz komponent pomocniczy,
to still be able to do that.
aby nadal mc to zrobi.
So let's navigate all the way up to the hoc folder and import the auxiliary component from the aux.js
Przejdmy wic a do folderu HLC i zaimportujmy komponent pomocniczy z acucha ox,
file,
jako wypeniony.
now I will simply add the axillary component as a wrapper around this component and it should now work
Teraz po prostu dodabym element pachowy jako wrapper wok tego komponentu i powinien teraz dziaa, a modalnie
and modal of course is wrong,
oczywicie jest le.
this is backdrop here.
To jest to tutaj.
So now that we get a backdrop as part of the sideDrawer too, if we reload the application
Dziki temu, gdy przeadujemy aplikacj, dostaniemy to, ktre bdzie czci ciebie.
we don't see that though. Where is the backdrop?
Nie widzimy tego jednak, gdzie jest to.
Well if you inspect the backdrop, you of course realize it has this show property which needs to be true
C, jeli sprawdzasz to, to oczywicie zdajesz sobie spraw, e ma on waciwo show, ktra musi by
to actually display it.
prawdziwa, aby j faktycznie wywietli.
So of course we can simply set show like this and since it is a boolean property, we don't need to assign
Oczywicie moemy po prostu ustawi taki program, a poniewa jest to waciwo boolowska, nie musimy przypisywa wartoci,
a value. Just by adding it, it will be set to true, if it's not present like before, it will be set to false.
tylko dodajc j, zostanie ustawiona na warto true, jeli nie bdzie obecna, tak jak przed ustawieniem wartoci false.
So now we get the backdrop, looks nice.
Teraz mamy adne to.
Of course this should not always be visible though, the sideDrawer should only be shown sometimes
Oczywicie nie zawsze powinno to by widoczne, chocia paski boczne powinny by pokazywane tylko czasami.
once you click the menu button essentially and it should also be closed
Po klikniciu przycisku menu zasadniczo naley go rwnie zamkn.
once you click the backdrop.
Po klikniciu ta.
So for that, we need to register a click listener on the backdrop
W tym celu musimy zarejestrowa odbiornik klikni w tle.
and actually we already have one.
I tak ju mamy.
We have that click listener, clicked, which can fire any method we want to fire,
Mamy kliknitego klikacza, ktry moe uruchomi dowoln metod, ktr chcemy uruchomi.
so the goal is to now be able to handle this method in the sideDrawer.
Tak wic celem jest teraz mc obsuy t metod w bocznej szufladzie.
Now in the modal we simply propagate it, this click up so up to our holding container. Here in the
Teraz w ruchu, ktry nam propaguje, robi si tak a do naszego kontenera trzymajcego w szufladzie
sideDrawer,
bocznej.
I also want to do this. We could also have turned the sideDrawer into a stateful component and handle the
Te chc to zrobi, e wszyscy moglibymy odoy na bok albo do stanu penego komponentu i obsuy kliknicie
click in here with a method and with a state which we switch from show
tutaj z metod i ze stanem, ktry przeczamy z show.
so from true to false and so on and there would be nothing wrong with that but we will also trigger
Tak wic od prawdziwej do faszywej i tak dalej i nie byoby w tym nic zego, ale uruchomimy
the sideDrawer from the toolbar at the end because there we'll have this menu button.
rwnie boczn szuflad z paska narzdzi na kocu, poniewa bdzie tam jego przycisk menu.
So in the end we also need to create a connection from toolbar to sideDrawer and we have that connection
Koniec kocw musimy rwnie utworzy poczenie z paska narzdzi do bocznej szuflady i ju mamy
already,
to poczenie.
it's the layout component,
To jest komponent ukadu.
this is where we use both.
Tutaj uywamy obu.
So in my opinion, it makes more sense to turn the layout component into a class component where we can
Moim zdaniem bardziej sensowne jest przeksztacenie komponentu ukadu w komponent klasy, w
implement the method so that we can listen to both the sideDrawer closing itself by clicking on the backdrop
ktrym moemy zaimplementowa metod, abymy mogli sucha obu stron lub zamykajc si, klikajc na to,
as well as toolbar opening the sideDrawer by clicking on that toggle button.
a take pasek narzdzi otwierajcy stron lub klikajc na tym przycisku.
So therefore this is the next step,
Tak wic jest to kolejny krok.
I'll turn my layout here into a class, class Layout and it should extend a component therefore so import
Zmie mj ukad tutaj na ukad klasy i powinien on rozszerzy komponent, dlatego te
component from react and here simply extended with the extends keyword.
moesz zaimportowa komponent i zareagowa po prostu rozszerzeniem sowa kluczowego extents.
Now inside that layout class, we needs to render method as you learned
Teraz wewntrz tego ukadu klasa-B musi renderowa metod, jak si nauczye.
and then we should return some jsx and we get the jsx here.
A potem powinnimy zwrci j jako X i otrzymamy J jako x rok.
So let's simply cut it and enter it here,
Po prostu wytnijmy go i wprowadmy tutaj.
remove that stuff down there and props can now be accessed with this.props as you learned,
Usu te rzeczy tam, a rekwizyty mog by teraz dostpne dziki tym rekwizytom, tak jak si tego nauczye.
that's the case for all class based components.
Tak jest w przypadku wszystkich komponentw opartych na klasach.
Now the name change to Layout with a capital L due to the naming convention
Teraz nazwa zmienia si na acin na konwencj nazewnictwa Kapolei LTTE.
so let's also adjust the export down there.
Tak wic wszyscy posumy si eksportem.
Now with that we got our Layout component changed,
Teraz zmienilimy nasz komponent etykiety.
it's now a class.
To jest teraz klasa.
Now we can implement a method here and I will call this method sideDrawerClosedHandler,
Teraz moemy zaimplementowa tutaj metod i nazw tej metody zwrc si do naszego zamknitego programu obsugi.
you could of course take any name you want.
Mgby oczywicie wzi dowolne imi.
I'll use this syntax where I assign an ES6 arrow function to a property so that the this keyword
Uyj tej skadni, w ktrej przypisz twoj funkcj strzaki 6 do waciwoci, aby to sowo kluczowe w
inside this method will refer to the class at all times.
tej metodzie odnosio si do klasy przez cay czas.
And we also need to manage some state in here, state which I'll set up here should essentially contain
Musimy rwnie zarzdza jakim stanem w twoim stanie, ktry bdzie ustanowiony, powinien zasadniczo
information
zawiera informacje.
if the sideDrawer is visible or not. So here I'll set up
Jeli strona jest Weazel lub nie, wic wszystko gotowe.
showSideDrawer and set this to false initially maybe.
Poka boczn szuflad i ustaw to na pocztek moe.
Now let's set it to true for testing so that we can see it
Ustawmy j tak, aby bya testowana, abymy mogli j zobaczy.
and in sideDrawerClosedHandler
I wewntrz naszego zamknitego nonika.
I'll call this.setState and set showSideDrawer to false of course, like this.
Zadzwoni do tego ustawionego stanu i ustawi wycieczk lub dwa pola oczywicie.
So now I need to pass this event handler method here to my sideDrawer and I'll name it closed. There
Teraz musz przekaza t procedur obsugi zdarzenia do mojej bocznej szuflady, a ja nadam jej nazw zamknit tam, gdzie
we want to execute this sideDrawerClosedHandler,
chcemy wykona t stron losowania zamknitego programu obsugi.
so now we have to use that closed property in the sideDrawer and there I'll use it to simply pass it onto
Teraz musimy uy tej bliskiej waciwoci w bocznej szufladzie, a nastpnie uy jej po prostu do
the backdrop where I have this clicked property which will simply pass me the onClick event basically.
przeniesienia jej na to, w ktrym mam t kliknit waciwo, ktra po prostu przekae mi zdarzenie click on basic.
So there I want to pass on props.closed,
Wic chc przekaza rekwizyty zamknite.
so simply setting up this chain where I pass down the method reference to the place where I handle the
Po prostu konfiguruj ten acuch, w ktrym przekazuj odwoanie do metody do miejsca, w
click in the end.
ktrym obsuguj kliknicie na kocu.
So with that, show of course should also be bound dynamically,
Z tym pokazem oczywicie wszystko to wie si dynamicznie.
show should be bound to whatever you want to name it, lets say props.show what makes sense
Pokazy powinny by dozwolone, aby pozwoli na to, co chcesz nazwa, powiedzmy, e pokaz z propem ma sens, ale
but to not confuse it with this.show,
nie myli z tym show.
let's name it open.
Nazwijmy to otwartym.
So this open property then needs to be set on the sideDrawer,
Tak wic ta otwarta waciwo musi by ustawiona na bocznej szufladzie.
so back to the toolbar, we need to pass, excuse me, back to the Layout, we need to pass the open property to the
Wracajc do paska narzdzi, musimy przekaza mnie z powrotem do ukadu, ktrego potrzebujemy do otwartego obiektu na bok
sideDrawer to now
lub do teraz.
and that should be this.state.showSideDrawer because this will hold the information whether the
I to powinna by ta szuflada boczna pokazowa, poniewa bdzie ona zawiera informacj, czy drzwi
sideDrawer should be opened or not.
boczne powinny zosta otwarte, czy nie.
With these additions, if we now save all the files and we go back, we should still have the backdrop
Z tymi dodatkami, jeli teraz zapiszemy wszystkie pliki i wrcimy, nadal powinnimy mie to.
but if we click it, it should dismiss the backdrop,
Ale jeli go klikniemy, powinien on odrzuci to.
it doesn't dismiss the sideDrawer yet because we haven't added any logic to do so.
Nie odrzuca strony Drori, poniewa nie dodalimy do tego adnej logiki.
Let's add this logic now and in this sideDrawer, remember that I added this open and close css class
Dodajmy teraz t logik, aw bocznej szufladzie pamitaj, e dodaem t otwart i zamknit klas C S S wewntrz
in the sideDrawer css file.
szuflady C S S file.
I want to attach these classes conditionally because they will basically move the sideDrawer out of the
Chc przywiza te klasy warunkowo, poniewa bd one zasadniczo porusza si na zewntrz lub
page or into it and they will play an animation with it due to that transition property here.
poza stron lub do niego i bd odtwarza animacj z powodu tej waciwoci przejcia tutaj.
So therefore we need to conditionally attached the open or close css classes
Dlatego musimy warunkowo przywiza Ci do otwarcia lub zamknicia jako klasy.
and then the sideDrawer component, that is the part I want to do before I return code here,
A nastpnie komponent boczny, ktry jest czci, ktr chc wykona, zanim zwrc kod tutaj.
before I return jsx. I want to create a constant which I'll name attachedClasses and there, that should
Zanim zwrc J jako X, chc utworzy sta nazw Witchella doczon do klas i tam, ktra
always contain my sideDrawer class
powinna zawsze zawiera mj cydr lub Clauss.
but the next element in this array by default could be the closed class,
Ale nastpnym elementem w desire domylnie moe by zamknicie klasy.
so Classes.close,
Wic klasy si zamykaj.
that's of course referring to that close css class
To oczywicie odnosi si do tej Colloseum S-Class.
Now the open class should be added when open, that property is true.
Teraz otwrz klas ponownie, gdy ta waciwo jest prawdziwa.
So I will then check if props.open,
Tak wic sprawdz, czy podpora jest otwarta.
if this is true, the attachedClasses should actually not have to Close class but the Open Class
Jeli jest to prawd, klauzule attach nie powinny w rzeczywistoci zamyka klasy, ale klasy Open.
so that return this from a constant to a variable
Tak wic zwrot jest od staej do zmiennej.
so they can reset it here. attachedClasses should now be an array where I do have my sideDrawer but where I
Wic mog zresetowa swoje klauzule doczania roku powinny by teraz tablic, gdzie mam swoje boczne drzwi, ale
also have my open class and now I can use the down here where I assign a class name.
mamy te moj otwart klas i teraz mog uy tutaj, gdzie przypisz nazw klasy.
I won't assign classes sideDrawer, I will assign my attachedClasses instead
Nie przypisuj klas cyder, bo zamiast tego przypisz swoje zajcia.
and since we can't pass an array of strings here but should pass a single string, I'll join that string
A poniewa nie moemy przekaza tutaj tablicy acuchw, ale powinnimy przekaza pojedynczy cig, cay wybr tego cigu
into a single string with whitespaces in between the items,
w pojedynczy cig z biaymi spacjami znajduje si pomidzy tymi elementami.
so in between my css classes. Now with that, we should have a drawer which actually can disappear as soon
Tak wic pomidzy teczkami mojej sjesty teraz, jeli tata powinnimy mie remis, ktry faktycznie moe znikn, gdy
as we click the backdrop and it does.
tylko klikniemy to i tak si stanie.
Next step is to create this toggle button here to also move it in once we click that button.
Nastpnym krokiem jest utworzenie tego celu, ale po klikniciu tego przycisku wszystkie powikszenia zostan przeniesione.